<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Qa | A Woman's Journey Through Technology]]></title>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/categories/qa/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-01-26T11:30:09-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://geekymamamare.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Susan Prestage]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Computer Background]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/06/01/my-computer-background/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-01T14:01:06-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/06/01/my-computer-background</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>First, some history to know where I come from, technologically.</p>

<h3>Programming</h3>

<p>I discovered my passion for computers in a programming class I took in high school.  My gradual route through post-high school education eventually took me to the University of California at Santa Cruz.  I had initially planned to major in Computer Science, but when I discovered that they had a Computer Engineering program where I could learn all about hardware and still take programming classes as my upper division electives, I knew I&rsquo;d found the right program for me.  Years of hard work later saw me successfully earn my degree and employed in the computer industry as a software tester.</p>

<h3>Whoops, a job in test!</h3>

<p>I had initially planned to become a developer, but landed my first industry job at a startup that needed a tester immediately and I was the only one on their list willing to come in the very next day, a Saturday.  Yes, I had social plans, but the opportunity was not to be missed, considering the huge hiring freeze in Silicon Valley at the time.</p>

<h3>Quality Engineering</h3>

<p>Several industry quality engineering positions later, I decided that I very much liked testing, as long as I was working very much inside the development process.  I wanted to be in on the design decisions and debug the specs (specifications) <b>before</b> they were implemented and it was too late.</p>

<p>Slowly the industry changed, turning quality engineers into SDETs and requiring automation of monolithic systems where it&rsquo;s hard to feel like your testing, your coding, or your opinions matter much.  I had managed to avoid this side of the industry.  But now, it seemed to be the standard.  Another failed SDET interview in February seemed to confirm this.</p>

<p><br></p>

<center>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</center>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
